https://slama.dev/comeback/
https://slama.dev/comeback/
Bro, you definitely haven't had enough yet.
Brácha, určitě ještě nemáš dost.
I haven't even beaten my personal record yet.
Ještě jsem ani nevyrovnal osobák.
Ozzak!
Ozzáku!
You're drinking during work hours again.
Už zase pijete v pracovní době.
Hello, Marcelka.
Dobrý den, Marcelko.
Tomas, good day.
Tomáši, dobrý den.
You put up with this.
Vy mu to trpíte.
Next week is Premium Lager Days and Ozzak is defending the Golden Kidney there.
Příští týden jsou Dny prémiového ležáku a Ozzák tam obhajuje Zlatou ledvinu.
So I made an exception and let him train in the shop.
Tak jsem mu výjimečně dovolil trénovat v krámě.
Train?
Trénovat?
The Golden Kidney is the top prize in the beer pentathlon.
Zlatá ledvina je hlavní cena v pivním pětiboji.
He's training for the marathon right now.
Teď trénuje maraton.
What does this have to do with running?
Co má tohle společného s běháním?
It's about how many beers you can drink before you have to go to the bathroom.
Ale jde o to, kolik vypije piv, než bude muset na záchod.
Disgusting.
Odporné.
You haven't seen the freestyle event yet.
No to jste ještě neviděla po volné jízdě.
I mean Ozzak.
Myslím Ozzáka.
I mean the competition.
Myslím tu soutěž.
Thank God for the pentathlon.
Zaplať pánbůh za pětiboj.
When he did the Nordic combined, it was worse.
Když dělal severskou kombinaci, bylo to horší.
That's drinking on skis?
To je pití na lyžích?
A liter of vodka, sauna, and then hammer throw.
Litr vodky, sauna a potom hod kladivem.
Prague '17.
Prácha sedmnáct.
Will he be able to look after the shop in this state when we're in Bruntal?
Bude schopen se v tomhle stavu postarat o obchod, až budeme v Bruntále?
Where?
Kde?
In Bruntal.
V Bruntále.
I've arranged a concert for you there next week.
Domluvila jsem vám tam na příští týden koncert.
Jesus Mary, woman, have you lost your mind?
Ježíši Maria, ženská, zbláznila jste se?
Allow me.
Dovolte.
You don't go to Bruntal, they have the worst audience.
Když do Bruntálu se nejezdí, tam je nejhorší publikum.
What kind of nonsense is that?
Co je to za nesmysl?
There are people there like everywhere else.
Jsou tam lidé jako všude jinde.
Everyone knows it.
Každej to ví.
Even Vlada Hron says so here in his Showbiz Calendar.
I Vláďa Hron to tady píše ve Svétským kalendáři.
Where?
Kde?
In the Showbiz Calendar.
Ve Svétským kalendáři.
It's his handbook for regional artists.
To je jeho příručka pro oblastní umělce.
You can see it right on the first page.
To hned vidíte na první stránce.
Three golden rules of Vlada Hron.
Tři zlatá pravidla Vládi Hrona.
Lip-sync is a safe bet,
Playback je jistota,
anything for television, and never take Bruntal.
v televizi cokoliv a Bruntál nebrat.
There are terrible things written about Bruntal in here.
O Bruntálu se tady píšou hrozný věci.
Tomas, I spoke with the mayor and he said Mr. Hron is getting back at them for that unfortunate misunderstanding after his concert.
Tomáši, mluvila jsem se starostou a ten říkal, že pan Hron se jim mstí za to nešťastné nedorozumění po jeho koncertu.
What misunderstanding?
Jaké nedorozumění?
He wouldn't say, but he emphasized that they're currently not asphalting anywhere and feathers are extremely scarce.
No to neříkal, ale zdůraznil, že se u nich v současné době nikde neasfaltuje a peří je vyloženě nedostatkové.
And that's supposed to calm me down?
A to mě má jako uklidnit?
Bruntal people are very tough and all my songs are about love.
Bruntálci jsou velmi drsní lidé a já mám všechny písničky o lásce.
Bruntal's happiest period was in 1964 when the army experimentally added LSD to the water supply.
Nejšťastnější období zažil Bruntál v roce 1964, kdy armáda experimentálně přidávala LSD do vodovodního řadu.
But things must have improved since then.
Ale od té doby se to určitě zlepšilo.
Yeah?
Jo?
In '84 they made Mencik cry there.
Ve čtyřaosmdesátým tam rozplakali Menčíka.
But they're really looking forward to you.
Ale na vás se moc těší.
They even sent a deposit just for a promise of a performance.
Dokonce poslali zálohu jen za příslib vystoupení.
Socks?
Fusekle?
Sixty pairs of socks in dove grey.
Šedesát pár ponožek barvy holubičí šedi.
They're quite nice.
Jsou docela hezké.
And fireproof.
A nehořlavé.
Are you kidding?
Děláte si srandu?
It's a rough region.
Je to drsný kraj.
And they also included an information brochure.
A ještě přibalili informační brožurku.
And this would be your first district town, not counting Zlin.
A bylo by to vaše první okresní město, když nepočítám Zlín.
That was a big lesson, Marcelka, a big lesson.
To byla velká lekce, Marcelko, velká lekce.
Well, see, and in Bruntal they'll let you sing.
No vidíte, a v Bruntále vás zazpívat nechají.
They nearly tore my arms off, I had to promise them an encore.
Málem mi utrhaly ruce, musela jsem jim přislíbit přídavek.
Really?
Vážně?
Tomas, I can feel it in my bones that this will be a success.
Tomáši, cítím v kostech, že to bude sukces.
As long as we don't underestimate the preparation.
Když nepodceníme přípravu.
The journey to Bruntal takes somewhere between six and twenty hours.
Cesta do Bruntálu trvá něco mezi šesti a dvaceti hodinami.
How come?
Jak to?
The mayor said it depends on whether it's the rainy season.
Starosta říkal, že záleží na tom, jestli je zrovna období dešťů.
And when is the rainy season in Bruntal?
A kdy je v Bruntále období dešťů?
All year round.
Celý rok.
Well, except for April Two.
Tedy, kromě dubna dva.
What's April Two?
Co to je duben dva?
That's what they call July.
Tak říkají červenci.
I don't understand how you can keep drinking after twenty beers.
Nechápu, jak si po dvaceti pivech můžete dávat další.
I'm doing a cooldown.
Vyklusávám.
How many?
A kolik?
About a minute.
Asi minuta.
About a minute?
Asi minuta?
What do you mean about a minute?
Jak asi minuta?
What's that supposed to be?
Co to má být?
Damn it, Mambo, you're a lousy timekeeper.
Sakra, mambo, vy jste časomíra na houby.
48.
48.
There you go.
No prosím.
That's more like it.
To je jiná.
Forty.
Čtyřicet.
Again.
Tak znova.
But without me.
Ale beze mně.
Hey, bro clearly told you to time me.
Hejte, brácho, váš jasně řekl, že mi to máte měřit.
But he didn't say how many times.
Ale neříkal kolikrát.
Crap, this won't be good.
No do prčic, to nebude dobrý.
Seems fine to me.
Mně už to dobrý připadá.
No!
Ne!
The guy from Pilsen did the half-pint in under thirty.
Trubka z Plzně udělal políčit pod třicet.
Radim.
Radim.
Hey.
Čau.
Practicing the straw?
Trénuješ brčko?
Tomas isn't here.
Tomáš tu není.
He went to buy some dentures.
Šel koupit nějaký protézy.
He'll be back in a moment.
Za moment je naspátek.
Damn, and I have to run.
Sakra, a já musím letět.
Could you help me?
Vy byste mi nepomohla?
I'm going to the employment office, I'm not sure if I filled out their form correctly.
Jdu na pracovák, nevím, jestli jsem ten jejich formulář vyplnila správně.
Especially the job requirements section here.
Tady hlavně požadavky na zaměstnání.
What's so hard about writing "waitress"?
Co je na tom těžkého napsat servírka?
She doesn't want the job, does she?
Nechce tu práci, ne?
Something like at the Badger.
O trochu jako u Jezevce.
Requirements for working hours.
Požadavky na pracovní dobu.
Seventeen hours max. Well, that max can be minimum, every other Sunday work fully clothed.
Sedmnáct hodin max. No to max. může na minimálně, každou druhou neděli pracovat kompletně oblečená.
Is it excessive?
Je to přehnaný?
No.
Ne.
Great.
Bezva.
I want a job, but a tough accountant.
Chci práci, ale vostrý počtář.
Mambo, let's go.
Mambo, jdeme.
Now!
Teď!
I'm off then.
Tak já letím.
Good luck and don't let them rattle you.
Ať vám to dobře dopadne a nenechte se rozhodit.
Why?
Proč?
At the employment office they always had a laugh at Mambo's expense.
Na pracáku měli vždycky z mamby.
Really?
Fakt?
I wanted to confirm my average income and they sent me bus papers by mail.
Chtěla jsem potvrdit průměrný příjem a poštou mi přišly papíry na autobus.
I see.
Aha.
At first I wanted to yell at them, but then I realized the bus actually comes in handy sometimes.
Nejdřív jsem na ně kvůli tomu chtěla řvát, ale pak jsem zjistila, že se občas docela hodí.
There has to be chaos at the government offices.
No bordel na úřadech musí bejt.
If they had things in order at social services, I could forget about those guide dog allowances.
Kdyby měli pořádek na sociálce, tak můžu na ty příspěvky na slepeckýho psa úplně zapomenout.
Well, it's not much, five grand a year, but they throw in a bag of really good kibble.
No ne, že by to bylo moc, pět kilo za rok, ale dávaj k tomu pytel moc dobrých granulí.
Aren't you worried they'll catch on?
To se nebojíte, že vám na to přijdou?
In five years they only came to check once, and luckily in summer.
Ale za pět let mě přišli zkontrolovat jenom jednou a naštěstí v létě.
You pretended to be on vacation.
Dělala jste, že jste na dovolené.
No, Lexa let them in, but luckily I was wearing sunglasses.
Ne, Lexa je pustil dovnitř, ale já jsem naštěstí na sobě měla sluneční brejle.
So all I had to do was bump into the wardrobe a few times and yell "Barik."
Takže stačilo párkrát vrazit do skříně a zařvat Baríku.
Now I get the tram for free too.
Teď mám za darmo i tramvaj.
Time!
Čas!
Pardon?
Pardon?
I have a time.
Čas mám.
Thirty... six.
Třicet... šest.
The guy would have downed the half-pint in that time.
Trubka by za tu dobu vytáhl tu flák.
So bye.
Tak čau.
Jesus, uncle, what happened?
Ježíš, strejdo, co se děje?
Nothing, I was practicing triple-chug and the pint glass slipped.
A nic, trénuju trojlok a vyklouzl mi půllitr.
Aren't you overdoing the training a bit?
Nepřeháníš to s tím tréninkem nějak?
Listen girl, talent isn't everything.
No holčičko, talent není všecko.
I just don't want you to be overtrained.
Já jenom, abys nebyl přetrénovanej.
You're probably right.
Asi máš pravdu.
Maybe I'll call Pitl and tell him I'm skipping synchronized drinking this year and just doing the pentathlon.
Možná zavolám Pitlovi, že letos na synchronizovaný chlastání kašlu a budu dělat jenom pětiboj.
Brutal.
Krut jsi.
Uncle, what's wrong with you?
Strejdo, co to s tebou je?
I'm kind of nervous, you know.
Já jsem nějakej nervózní, no.
About what?
A z čeho?
You've won the Golden Kidney four times in a row.
Vždyť jsi Zlatou ledvinu vyhrál čtyřikrát za sebou.
But this year they've allowed professionals to compete.
Jenomže tenhle rok povolili účast profíkům.
What professionals?
Jak profíkům?
Fibbinger is coming, he drinks first league in Germany.
Přijede Fibbinger, ten chlastá v Německu první ligu.
So do you.
No to ty taky.
We don't have a league here, Ivuska.
My tady žádnou ligu nemáme, Ivuško.
We're all registered as amateurs.
Všichni jsme registrovaní jako amatéři.
What?
Cože?
Fibbinger is a pro from the Fazby League.
Fibbinger je profík z Fazby ligy.
They say a week before a meet he sleeps buried in salt to build up a thirst.
Říká se o něm, že týden před mítinkem spí zasypanej solí, aby chytil žízeň.
Wait, he actually makes a living doing this?
Moment, on se tím jako fakt živí?
Well you know, Germany, they've always been ahead.
To víš, Německo, tam byli vždycky dál.
And his conditions.
Ty moje podmínky.
Special training pubs.
Speciální tréninkový hospody.
Training camp at Oktoberfest and equipment you can only dream of.
Soustředění na Oktoberfestu a vybavení, o jakým se ti ani nezdá.
Teflon straws.
Teflonový brčka.
And me?
A já?
Three old shot glasses, a straw you used, and a paper bag instead of a starting pistol.
Tři starý panáky, brčko po tobě a místo startovací pistole papírový pytlík.
And Mambo keeps my time!
A čas mi měří mamba!
So Mr. Burda, that's a 500 crown fine for yelling at government offices.
Tak pane Burda, to máme za 500 korun pokuty za řvaní na úřadech.
Pay at the cashier's window.
Stavte se s tím na pokladně.
Yeah.
Jo.
Next!
Další!
Come in, have a seat.
Přejděte, posaďte se.
I'm out of work, so I thought you could help me.
Já jsem bez práce, tak jsem si říkala, že byste mi mohli pomoct.
Are you a college graduate?
Jste vysokoškolačka?
No.
Ne.
That's a relief.
Tak to se mi ulevilo.
Is this your first time here?
Jste tu poprvé?
Yeah.
Jo.
Sign this here for me.
Tak mi to tuhle podepište.
What is it?
Co to je?
That you've been informed about the ban on yelling at government offices.
Že jste byla seznámena se zákazem řvaní na úřadech.
I see.
Aha.
We've been having some problems with that lately.
Máme s tím poslední dobou trochu problémy.
You really worked as the sole employee of a non-stop?
Opravdu jste pracovala jako jediný zaměstnanec nonstop?
Yeah.
No.
And you never closed?
A to jste nikdy nezavřela?
Once for 20 minutes.
Jednou na 20 minut.
My son fell out of a window.
Syn vypadl z okna.
For twenty minutes?
Na dvacet minut?
Well, I had to go open the building for him, he couldn't reach the doorbells yet.
No, musela jsem mu jít otevřít barák, ještě nedosáhl na zvonky.
I see.
Aha.
So, Mrs. Buckova, I'll register you in the computer now.
Tak, paní Bučková, já vás teď tady založím v počítači.
Since it's your first time, you don't even know how much easier everything is now that we've been connected to ISSS.
Protože jste tu poprvé, tak ani nevíte, o co je to teď všechno jednodušší, co nás připojili k ISSS.
To what?
K čemu?
Integrated System of State Administration.
Integrovaný systém státní správy.
Look, it's all Greek to me too.
Helejte, pro mě je to taky španělská vesnice.
It's like a big computer that knows everything.
Je to něco jako velkej počítač, který ví všechno.
Absolutely everything?
Úplně všechno?
Absolutely.
Úplně.
All the offices are on it now.
Už jsou na tom všechny úřady.
From the veterinary administration to the land registry.
Od veterinární správy po katastr nemovitostí.
Before, you had to run around to all of them yourself.
Dřív jste si to všechno musela oběhnout sama.
And today all I need to do is type in your birth number and it pulls up everything about you.
A dneska stačí naťukat vaše rodný číslo a vyjede mi to tu o vás komplet.
Whether you pay taxes, what social benefits you receive, whether you owe anything on health insurance, or what your milk yield is.
Jestli platíte daně, jaký pobíráte dávky na sociální, jestli nemáte dluhy na zdravotní, nebo jakou máte dojivost.
One moment.
Moment.
Vera, hey, Holstein cattle breeding charts showed up on my screen.
Věra, hele, objevily se mi tam plemenný tabulky holštínskýho skotu.
Yours too?
Tobě taky?
Actually, how do I get rid of it?
Vlastně a jak to zruším?
I can't.
Nezruším.
Ah, okay then.
Aha, tak fajn.
Bye.
Čau.
So, please, fill this out and then come back.
Tak, prosím vás, tohle si vyplníte a potom přijďte.
Thank you.
Tak děkuju.
Bye.
Nashle.
In recent years, with the support of the European Union, the devastated landscape has been restored to its original character.
V posledních letech byl s podporou Evropské unie vrácen zdevastované krajině její původní ráz.
The Armageddon summit?
Zasedání Armageddon?
No, that's the Bruntal region before recultivation.
Ne, to je Bruntálsko před rekultivací.
And now let's recall what Bruntal looked like before recultivation.
A teď si připomeneme, jak vypadal Bruntál před rekultivací.
Do you really have to?
Fakt to musíš?
Marcelka already signed the contract.
Marcelka už podepsala smlouvu.
Malicious tongues claim that Bruntal people don't like to have fun.
Zlé jazyky tvrdí, že Bruntálci se neradi baví.
Nothing could be further from the truth.
Nic nemůže být dále od pravdy.
In Bruntal, some colorful pastimes were actually born.
V Bruntálu se některé rázovité kratochvíle dokonce zrodily.
Besides hunting pregnant does, there's mainly the legendary race called the Silage Bullet.
Vedle lovu březích laní se jedná hlavně o legendární běžecký závod Silážní střela.
Dad?
Tati?
One moment.
Moment.
Why is it printed on the back of a funeral announcement?
Proč je to z druhé strany natištěno na parte?
What?
Co?
They say they're saving there.
Prý tam šetří.
In archival footage we see a group of competitors gathering at the bottom of a silage pit.
Na archivních záběrech vidíme skupinu závodníků, jak se schází na dně silážní jámy.
The hunters are already loaded, so we'll wait for the gunshot.
Myslivci už mají nabito, takže si teď počkáme na výstřel.
I'm not going anywhere.
Já nikam nejdu.
Pardon, but you gave me the wrong form.
Pardon, ale vy jste mi dala špatný formulář.
Sorry.
Promiňte.
This says application for a long-distance pipeline construction permit.
No tady je napsaný žádost o povolení stavby dálkového potrubí.
That's fine.
To je v pořádku.
But I don't want to build a pipeline.
Ale já nechci stavět potrubí.
You know, when we order them through the system, sometimes different ones show up.
Prosím vás, jak to objednáváme přes systém, tak občas přijdou jiný.
So we don't make a big deal out of it and use what we have.
No tak z toho neděláme vědu a používáme, co máme.
And how am I supposed to fill it out?
A jak to máme jako vyplnit?
Normally.
Normálně.
In the "cadastral area" box write your name, in "number of compressor stations" put the number of children.
Do kolonky katastrální území napíšete jméno, do počtu kompresorových stanic počet dětí.
There's a sample filled out on the bulletin board on the second floor.
Vzorově to máte vyplněný na nástěnce ve druhém patře.
Anything else?
Ještě něco?
The last wolf in the Bruntal region was killed in 2008.
Poslední vlk na Bruntálsku byl zabit v roce 2008.
The hunter was fourteen-year-old Ingo Wovs.
Lovcem byl čtrnáctiletý Ingo Wovs.
Weapon used?
Použitá zbraň?
A flail.
Cep.
I should probably stop reading this or I'll dream about the Silage Bullet.
Asi bych to měl přestat číst, nebo se mi bude zdát o Silážní střele.
Come on bro, don't do this to me!
Tak nabrácha, tohle mi nedělej!
I seriously can't train here!
Tady se vážně nedá trénovat!
Sorry, can't you see my nerves are shot?
No tak promiň, tak vidíš, že mám nervy v kýblu, ne?
Fine, I'll leave the sprint for morning.
Dobře, sprint nechám na ráno.
I'll set up a track for the triple-chug.
Postavím si dráhu na trojlok.
Bruntal is scaring me more and more.
Ten Bruntál mě děsí čím dál tím víc.
Klistak is from Bruntal.
Klišťák je z Bruntálu.
He could tell you what it's like there.
Ten by ti mohl říct, jak to u nich chodí.
I'd rather not hear anything more.
Já už radši nechci nic slyšet.
Well, he doesn't say much anyway.
No, on toho taky moc nenamluví.
He just sits there, drinks his little beer, and draws frogs with teeth.
Ponad si jenom sedí, pije to svoje pivečko a maluje žáby se zubama.
And here we go.
A jdeme na to.
You drank my track.
Vypil jsi mi dráhu.
I haven't seen a triple-chug like that in a long time.
Takový trojlok jsem dlouho neviděl.
This is what government administration does to a person.
Tohle s člověkem udělá státní správa.
Just packing a few things for the trip.
Jen balím pár drobností na cestu.
Marcelka, I've made up my mind.
Marcelko, už jsem se rozhodl.
I'm not going to Bruntal.
Do Bruntálu nejedu.
You talked to Hron, didn't you?
Že vy jste mluvil s Hronem.
I went to see him, but someone hit him with a flail.
Stavoval jsem se za ním, ale někdo ho praštil cepem.
So he's in the ICU.
Takže leží na JIPce.
Tomas, why are you stressing about this?
Tomáši, proč se tím tak stresujete?
Bruntal is a town like any other today.
Teď Bruntál je město jako každé jiné.
And did you know that the word Bruntal comes from the German Freudenthal, meaning happy valley?
A víte, že slovo Bruntál pochází z německého Freudenthal, tedy šťastné údolí?
Yesterday they reported a cougar on the loose there.
Včera hlásili, že se tam toulá puma.
Don't be afraid of anything.
Ničeho se nebojte.
I spoke with the mayor.
Mluvila jsem se starostou.
He made a deal with the Wovs family and as soon as Ingo gets back from Prague, he'll sort it out.
Dohodl se s Wovsovými a jen co se Ingo vrátí z Prahy, dá to do pořádku.
No, I'm not going.
Ne, nejedu.
Have you read the contract?
Četl jste smlouvu?
Of course, though there's one letter in it I don't recognize.
Jistě, i když je tam jedno písmeno, které neznám.
That's a hard F, a regional specialty.
To je tvrdé F, krajová zvláštnost.
Have you read the cancellation terms? They're on the other side.
Četl jste podmínky odstoupení od smlouvy? Jsou na druhé straně.
Under the names of the deceased's sons: Ingo, Viktor, and Wolf with families.
Tam pod tím jménem pozůstalých synové Ingo, Viktor a Wolf s rodinami.
The only acceptable excuse for canceling is illness.
Omluvou pro zrušení produkce může být pouze nemoc.
Even then you'd pay a forty thousand crown penalty.
Ani tak byste platil čtyřicet tisíc pokuty.
For God's sake, where would I get forty thousand?
Proboha, kde bych vzal čtyřicet tisíc?
Or the equivalent in frog skins.
Nebo ekvivalent v žabích kůžích.
Then call them and say I have the flu.
Tak jim tam zavolejte, že mám chřipku.
Unfortunately, in the Bruntal region the flu isn't considered an illness but a sign of weakness.
Bohužel, chřipka na Bruntálsku není brána jako nemoc, ale jako změkčilost.
What counts as an illness there?
Co se tam uznává jako nemoc?
A gunshot wound or a fracture.
Průstřel nebo zlomenina.
And regarding your last employment?
A k vašemu poslednímu zaměstnání?
I mined mud.
Těžil jsem bahno.
Bruntal?
Bruntál?
And why did you leave?
No a proč jste odešel?
Ran out of mud.
Došlo bahno.
Excuse me for a minute.
Omluvám se na minutku.
Is it necessary?
Je to nutné?
Yes.
Je.
This morning I found this envelope in your mailbox.
Ráno jsem u vás v kaštlíku našla tuhle obálku.
And what about it?
No a co je s ní?
It contains a military draft order to a motorized rifle unit in Pribram.
Je v ní povolávací rozkaz k motostřelecké jednotce do Příbrami.
Wait.
Moment.
The computer apparently flagged you as an unconvicted white male.
Počítač vás zřejmě vyhodnotil jako netrestaného bílého muže.
Under 25, in good physical condition.
No, do 25 let, v dobré fyzické kondici.
And what do we do about it?
No a co s tím uděláme?
We'll cancel it.
Tak to zrušíme.
Yeah, right.
Jo, dřív.
You'd have to run around to a lot of places.
To byste toho musela obejít.
The military administration, the registry, the gynecologist, and the district court.
Vojenskou správu, matriku, gynekologa a obvodního soudu.
The gynecologist?
Gynekologa?
To confirm that you're a woman.
Aby potvrdil, že jste žena.
Today all you need to do is type in your birth number.
Dneska stačí naťukat vaše rodný číslo.
Hymenoptera.
Blanokřídlí.
Unfortunately.
Tak bohužel.
Military administration, registry, gynecologist, district court.
Vojenská správa, matrika, gynekolog, obvodní soud.
Here you go.
Prosím.
Vera, please, they showed up on my screen again.
Věra, prosím tě, objevili se mi tam.
Yours too, huh.
Jo, tobě taky.
So that's that.
Tak to je.
Wait, Mrs. Buckova, please, at the gynecologist tell them to put your name under "estimated annual extraction volume" and your sex under "vegetation."
Moment, paní Bučková, prosím vás, na té gyndě vyřiďte, ať vaše jméno napíšou pod předpokládaný roční objem těžby a pohlaví do rubriky porost.
So we don't have a mess here later, okay?
Ať v tom tady pak nemáme zmatek, jo?
Actually, Vera, how do I delete this?
Vlastně, prosím tě, a jak to zruším?
I can't.
Nezruším.
Ah, bye.
Aha, pa.
Well, I'm off.
Tak já jdu.
So tomorrow, are you excited?
Tak zítra, těšíte se?
Very, very excited.
Moc, moc se těším.
Tomorrow Bruntal, the day after maybe Ostrava.
Zítra Bruntál, pozítří třeba Ostrava.
We'll hit the road at seven in the morning.
Z trasy vyrazíme už v sedm ráno.
We still need to practice putting on snow chains.
No musíme ještě nacvičit nasazování sněhových řetězů.
But of course, it's May after all.
A samozřejmě, vždyť je květen.
February Two, Tomas.
Únor dva, Tomáši.
All right, bro, here I go!
Tak, brácha, jdu na to!
Break a leg, bro.
Tak, zlom vaz, brácha.
Wait, you're not coming to watch?
Počkej, ty se nepřijdeš podívat?
Mr. Pacovsky needs to get some sleep before the trip.
Pan Pacovský se musí vyspat před cestou.
But I'll come, of course I'll come, just let me stop by Simona's first.
Ale přijdu, samozřejmě, že přijdu, jen se ještě stavím za Simonou.
Is Mom home?
Maminka je doma?
She said she'd be back either at eight or when her shift ends.
Říkala, že přijde buď v osm, nebo až jí skončí příjem.
Then I'll wait for her.
No tak já na ni počkám.
Bro.
Brácha.
And if I win, you can hand me the flag when I drink the honorary beer.
A jestli vyhraju, můžeš mi podat vlajku, až budu dávat čestný pivečko.
What is this?
Co to je?
It's got the wrong colors right now.
Teď to má špatný barvy.
What do you mean wrong colors?
Jak špatný barvy?
White like foam, yellow like beer.
Bílá jako pěna, žlutá jako pivo.
I see.
Aha.
And the green?
A ta zelená?
Green.
Zelená.
Vera.
Věra.
Hey, I got a firearms license.
Hele, přišel mi zbrojní lístek.
Do you know what that is?
Nevíš, co to je?
A commendation?
Pochvala?
Well, great.
No bezva.
Look, I was really freaked out.
Hele, já jsem fakt lekl.
A commendation used to always be a transit visa.
Pochvala přece vždycky bývala průjezdní vízum.
What, they sent that to you?
No, cože, to poslal tobě?
A mining permit decision, yeah?
Rozhodnutí o povolení těžby, jo?
Jesus, and what did you do?
Ježíš, a co jsi provedla?
I have to go, I've got a client.
Prosím tě, musím končit, mám tu stranu.
Buckova, Simona, I don't want to go to the army.
Bučková, Simona, nechci na vojnu.
Okay, okay, okay.
No, dobře, dobře, dobře.
Jeez, but you'll have to go to the gynecologist again.
Ježíš, ale na tu gynekologii budete muset znova.
The system sent the correct forms.
Systém poslal správný formuláře.
They're white on black, but hopefully your gynecologist has a white pencil.
Jsou teda bílý na černým, ale snad má váš gynekolog bílou tužku.
What is it?
Co je?
You have to break my hand.
Musíš mi zlomit ruku.
Say "all you need is to type in your birth number" and I'll break both.
Řekni, stačí naťukat vaše rodný číslo, zlomím ti obě.
All you need is to type in your birth number.
Stačí naťukat vaše rodný číslo.
Then we'll both feel better.
Tak oběma nám bude líp.
But this is the left one.
Ale tohle je levá.
I don't care.
To je mi jedno.
But I do.
Ale mně ne.
The left one is hand number two.
Levá je ruka dvě.
Then the right one.
Tak pravou.
Bye.
Čau.
Lock the door properly.
Pořádně se zavři.
No, what are you doing?
Ne, co děláš?
Breaking your hand.
Lámu ti ruku.
Like this? But it'll hurt.
Ale takhle, vždyť to bude bolet.
For crying out loud, you wanted your hand broken, didn't you?
Do prčic, chtěl jsi zlomit ruku, ne?
I mean, where does such brutality come from?
Myslím si, kde se v tobě bere taková surovost?
So do you want your hand broken or not?
Tak chceš zlomit ruku, nebo ne?
But without anesthesia, you're acting like a butcher.
Ale bez umrtvení, vždyť ty se chováš jako řezník.
Then anesthetize yourself somehow.
Tak si to nějak umrtvi.
Ready?
Už?
One more spring blend.
Ještě jarní směs.
Tomas is going to kill me.
Tomáš je ze mě na plánu.
Good evening, Simona.
Dobrý večer, Simono.
Bruntal called.
Volal Bruntál.
We have to leave immediately.
Musíme vyrazit okamžitě.
Marcelka, please, could you wait outside for a moment?
Marcelko, prosím vás, nemůžete chvilku počkat venku?
I'm here with Simona...
Já tady se Simonou...
We don't have a minute.
Nemáme ani minutu.
The mayor said the frogs started migrating unexpectedly early this year.
Starosta říkal, že žáby začaly letos migrovat nečekaně brzy.
Did you say frogs?
Říkala jste žáby?
I meant frogs.
Chtěla jsem říct žáby.
We should take the Pulnek route.
Máme to vzít přes Půlnek.
That one's still holding.
Ten se ještě drží.
Then hurry up and go pack.
No tak rychle běžte si zabalit.
Do you have motion sickness pills?
Kinedril máte?
The pontoon bridge over the Lobnik has loose ropes.
Pontonový most přes Lobník má uvolněná lana.
See?
Vidíš?
If you weren't such a coward, you could already be happily howling in pain.
Kdybys nebyl srab, už jsi mohl v klidu skučet bolestí.
With a stunning triple-chug, Czech competitor Pacovsky has closed the gap from the straw event.
Strhujícím trojlokem český závodník Pacovský dotáhl ztrátu z brčka.
And the thrilling duel between him and the German Fibbinger will be decided by the final royal discipline.
A napínavý souboj mezi ním a Němcem Fibbingerem rozhodne teda až závěrečná královská disciplína.
The marathon!
Maraton!
And while the competitors prepare, let's welcome once again Iron Zekon.
A než se borci připraví, přivítáme opět Železného Zekona.
Hey.
Čau.
Who's that?
Kdo to je?
Iron Zekon.
Železnej Zekon.
The strongest guy around.
Nejsilnější chlápek v okolí.
A looker.
Feša.
And insanely strong.
A šíleně silnej.
We met at the restrooms, he patted my shoulders.
Potkali jsme se na hajzlíkách, poplácal mě po ramínkách.
It hurt a bit, but now I can call him Zdenda.
Trochu to bolelo, ale teď mu můžu říkat Zdendo.
Yeah, he looks like he could have looked at that singer and scared him off.
Jo, ten vypadá, jak kdyby se pohlédal na toho zpěváka.
Sasenka, that's quite a strong man, isn't he?
Sašenko, to je ale silák, viď?
He's disgusting, he just destroys things, he's a mindless brute.
Je odporný, jenom ničí věci, je to nemyslící primitiv.
Well, honey, when a guy thinks, it's about how to fool you.
No ono, děvenko, když chlap myslí, tak na to, jak by tě oblbnul.
Your dad for example, now there's a great thinker.
Tvůj táta například, to je náramnej myslitel.
I'd rather read.
Já si radši čtu.
Sure.
Jasně.
We ask the competitors to report to the start of the final discipline.
Žádáme soutěžící, aby se dostavili na start poslední disciplíny.
Three competitors are lining up for the marathon.
K maratonu nastupují tři borci.
At table number one, the Czech number one and defending champion, representing the Czech Republic, Franta Ozzak-Pacovsky.
U stolu číslo jedna, česká jednička a obhájce titulu, reprezentant České republiky, Franta Ozzák-Pacovský.
Number two, the challenger from Germany, Herr Heino Fibbinger.
Číslo dvě, vyzývatel z Německa, Herr Heino Fibbinger.
And number three, Enzo Birneri, Italy.
A číslo tři, Enzo Birneri, Itálie.
And since Vlada Hron still hasn't come to, the marathon will be started by
A protože Vláďa Hron se stále ještě neprobral, maraton odstartuje
Iron Zekon.
Železný Zekon.
So, lads.
Tož chlapi.
Ready.
Připravit.
Set.
Pozor.
Oops, oh dear, I seem to have crushed it.
Ajej, ajej, tož jsem to nějak rozmáčkl.
Well, never mind, lads.
Tož nic, chlapi, no.
So drink up.
Tož chlastněte.
Go.
Čiň.
Ivuska.
Ivuško.
Dad, where are you?
Tati, kde seš?
They're already on their 21st beer.
Už jsou u 21. piva.
I came to say goodbye, I'm going to Bruntal.
Přišel jsem se rozloučit, jedu do Bruntálu.
You didn't chicken out.
Ty ses na to nevykašlal.
What's that under your coat?
Co to máš pod tím kabátem?
A bulletproof vest.
Neprůstřelnou vestu.
It's a tough region.
Je to drsný kraj.
If anything happens to me, I wrote everything down for you.
Kdyby se mi něco stalo, všechno jsem ti napsal.
It's on the fridge.
Máš to na lednici.
And say hi to Ozzak.
A pozdravuj Ozzáka.
Dad, Ozzak is heading for victory, won't you wait?
Tati, Ozzák jede na vítězství, to nepočkáš?
Marcela and Simona are already waiting in the car.
Marcela se Simonou už čekají v autě.
Dad!
Tati!
Mamma mia!
Mamma mia!
The Italian competitor ends at the insurmountable 21st beer.
Italský závodník skončil na nedobytém 21. pivu.
How will this end?
Jak tohle může skončit?
Will the Czechs succumb to Germanic thirst?
Podlehnou Čechy germánské žízni?
22 swigs, dawn is breaking!
22 tahů, bude svítat!
OZZAK!
OZZÁK!
Tomas, we said five minutes.
Tomáši, řekli jsme si pět minut.
I'm coming, sorry.
Už mám, bohužel.
Please.
Prosím.
I've got nothing left to lose.
Já už nemám co ztratit.
Laika.
Lajka.
The winning competitor may savor the honorary beer.
Vítězný borec si může vychutnat čestné pivečko.
Congratulations.
Gratuluju.
Oh, pardon.
Ó, pardon.
Thanks, Zdenda.
Díky, Zdendo.
Tomas, we're half an hour behind schedule.
Tomáši, máme půl hodiny zpoždění.
We're almost past Malicek.
To už je skoro za Malíček.
All right.
Dobře.
Bro.
Brácha.
You showed me the way, that I shouldn't give up.
Ukázal jsi mi cestu, že to nemám vzdávat.
I'll handle Bruntal, let's go!
Ten Bruntál zvládnu, jdeme!
Wait, you're going to Bruntal?
Počkej, ty jedeš do Bruntálu?
Yeah, I've got an encore there.
Jo, mám tam přídavek.
You must be one tough guy.
Ty musíš být tvrdý chlap.
I never dared go further than Krnov.
Já jsem se neodvážil dál jak do Krnova.
That's still pretty lucky.
To je ještě hodně štěstí.
Bye!
Ahoj!
Oh crap, again?
Ó sakra, zase?
That's it, that's it.
Je to tam, je to tam.
At least three, just the wrist.
Aspoň tři, prostě zápěstí.
That's too much.
A to je moc.
I'm not going anywhere, it's broken.
Nikam nejdu, je to zlomený.
Thirty-two.
Třicet dva.
You still haven't gone to the bathroom?
Ty jsi ještě nebyl na záchodě?
One more will fit in there.
Ještě jedno se tam vejde.
Vera.
Věra.
Oh, hi Vlasta.
No, ahoj, Vlasti.
I'm looking at it too.
Taky na to koukám.
What does it say?
Co mi to píše?
Carbon-based beings, you will be destroyed.
Bytosti na bázi uhlíku budete zničeny.
And there's a countdown in the bottom corner.
A dole v rohu odpočítávání.
You too?
Tobě taky?
Well, okay then.
Tak fajn.
Bye.
Pa.